all-things-photography.com 2018-12-23

# Privacy Policy for www.all-things-photography.com

**NOTE 21.05.18:** Please see our updated GDPR policy after our existing one below.

###  _EXISTING PRIVACY POLICY_

We recognize that your privacy is important. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information we receive and collect when you use **All Things Photography** , as well as some of the steps we take to safeguard information. We hope this will help you make an informed decision about sharing personal information with us.

 **All Things Photography** strives to maintain the highest standards of decency, fairness and integrity in all our operations. Likewise, we are dedicated to protecting our customers', consumers' and online visitors' privacy on our website.

### Personal Information

 **All Things Photography** collects personally identifiable information from the visitors to our website only on a voluntary basis. Personal information collected on a voluntary basis may include name, postal address, email address, company name and telephone number.

This information is collected if you request information from us, participate in a contest or sweepstakes, and sign up to join our email list or request some other service or information from us. The information collected is internally reviewed, used to improve the content of our website, notify our visitors of updates, and respond to visitor inquiries.

Once information is reviewed, it is discarded or stored in our files. If we make material changes in the collection of personally identifiable information we will inform you by placing a notice on our site. Personal information received from any visitor will be used only for internal purposes and will not be sold or provided to third parties.

### Use of Cookies and Web Beacons

We may use cookies to help you personalize your online experience. Cookies are identifiers that are transferred to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize the sites pages, or register with any of our site's services, a cookie enables **All Things Photography** to recall your specific information on subsequent visits.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies by modifying your Web browser; however, if you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the site.

A web beacon is a transparent image file used to monitor your journey around a single website or collection of sites. They are also referred to as web bugs and are commonly used by sites that hire third-party services to monitor traffic. They may be used in association with cookies to understand how visitors interact with the pages and content on the pages of a web site.

We may serve third party advertisements that use cookies and web beacons in the course of ads being served on our web site to ascertain how many times you’ve seen an advertisement. No personally identifiable information you give us is provided to them for cookie or web beacon use, so they cannot personally identify you with that information on our web site.

Some third-party advertisements may be provided by Google, which uses cookies to serve ads on this site. Google uses the DART cookie, which enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visits to this site and other sites on the Web. You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

Browsers can be set to accept or reject cookies or notify you when a cookie is being sent. Privacy software can be used to override web beacons. Taking either of these actions shouldn't cause a problem with our site, should you so choose.

### Children's Online Privacy Protection Act

This website is directed to adults; it is not directed to children under the age of 13. We operate our site in compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, and will not knowingly collect or use personal information from anyone under 13 years of age.

### Non-Personal Information

In some cases, we may collect information about you that is not personally identifiable. We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. The information collected is used solely for internal review and not shared with other organizations for commercial purposes.

### Release of Information

If **All Things Photography** is sold, the information we have obtained from you through your voluntary participation in our site may transfer to the new owner as a part of the sale in order that the service being provided to you may continue. In that event, you will receive notice through our website of that change in control and practices, and we will make reasonable efforts to ensure that the purchaser honours any opt-out requests you might make of us.

### How You Can Correct or Remove Information

We provide this privacy policy as a statement to you of our commitment to protect your personal information. If you have submitted personal information through our website and would like that information deleted from our records or would like to update or correct that information, please use our [Contact Us](https://all-things-photography.com/contact-us/ "Contact ATP") page.

### Updates and Effective Date

 **All Things Photography** reserves the right to make changes in this policy. If there is a material change in our privacy practices, we will indicate on our site that our privacy practices have changed and provide a link to the new privacy policy. We encourage you to periodically review this policy so that you will know what information we collect and how we use it.

### Agreeing to Terms

If you do not agree to **All Things Photography's** Privacy Policy as posted here on this website, please do not use this site or any services offered by this site.

Your use of this site indicates acceptance of this privacy policy.

###  _25.05.18: UPDATE TO INCLUDE GDPR EU LAWS AS AT 25th May 2018_

#### Who we are

Our website address is: [https://www.all-things-photography.com](https://www.all-things-photography.com/).

### What Personal Data We Collect and Why We Collect It

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact Forms

When you complete and send information through one of our contact forms, will will assume that it is:

  1. A request for a quote regarding our services
  2. To kindly let us know of any errors or mistakes on our website
  3. To get in touch with a general question or enquiry
  4. Requesting permission to send us reviews, articles or tutorials for publication on the All Things Photography website

Your information is kept private on our own database and will not be sold, given away or used in any way other than to reply and continue discussions in a private manner.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded Content From Other Websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

### Who We Share Your Data With and How Long We Retain Your Data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

### Who Else Can Access Your Personal Data

We do not share your Personal Data with strangers. Personal Data about you is in some cases provided to our trusted partners, in order to either make providing the service to you possible or to enhance your customer experience. We share your data with:

### Connected Third Parties:

  * Google Analytics – [View their policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?gl=GB&hl=en)
  * Askimet – [View their policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/)
  * WordPress – [View their policy](https://en.blog.wordpress.com/2018/05/14/new-privacy-features-and-updated-policies/)
  * Instagram – [View their policy](https://help.instagram.com/155833707900388)
  * Facebook – [View their policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy)

### What Rights You Have Over Your Data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

### Where We Send Your Data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

### Affiliate Disclaimer

In 2015, the [Federal Trade Commission released their new rules for Disclosure Compliance](https://www.ftc.gov/tips-advice/business-center/guidance/ftcs-endorsement-guides). These rules are set in place to ensure that readers or viewers of web media (blogs, YouTube videos etc)know if the blogger/presenter/site owner is sponsored, endorsed or partnered with a different company. In blog terms, the readers need to know if the blogger is making money by sharing a link or product.

In compliance with the FTC guidelines, please assume the following about links and posts on this site: Any/all of the links on all-things-photography.com are affiliate links of which I receive a small compensation from sales of certain items.

### What Are Affiliate Links?

Purchases are made on external company websites: When a reader clicks on an affiliate link located on all-things-photography.com to purchase an item, the reader buys the item from the seller directly and not from all-things-photography.com. Amazon and/or other companies pay all-things-photography.com a small commission or other compensation for promoting their website or products through their affiliate program.

Prices are exactly the same for you if your purchase is through an affiliate link or non-affiliate link. You won't pay more by clicking the link but the small commission earned helps us to maintain this site.
